

Toronto, ON (905) 226-3345 harpreetsi9h@gmail.com Portfolio - Website

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An aspiring Java Developer with around **5 years** of experience in java/software development practices such as coding, testing, code reviews, code comments, etc. A result oriented Java Developer looking for challenging career where I can implement my coding knowledge & further enhance my skills.

SKILLS

- Writing efficient, Maintainable, reusable Code with Solid understanding of object-oriented programming principles and multithreading and synchronization on multicore systems.
- Strong knowledge of Languages:
 Java, J2EE, JavaScript, JSON,
 Kotlin, Object-Oriented
 Programming (OOP) patterns and concepts.
- Problem-solving and Proficient in design, Debugging with attention to detail. Experience working in AGILE Methodology and collaborate in team environment by implementing Sprint & Scrum.
- Excellent verbal and written
 Communication, Team leadership and teamwork skills.
- Experienced in: Spring, Spring Boot, RESTful APIs, Java APIs, Microservices, Kubernetes, Kafka, MySQL, JDBC, JSP, Struts, Github, MVC, IntelliJ IDEA, TDD, Eclipse.
- Knowledge of: C/C++, HTML, CSS,
 JQuery, Python, React,
 TypeScript, Angular, Wordpress,
 NodeJs, MongoDB, Oracle DB,
 Azure Cloud, AWS.

EXPERIENCE

Java Developer

Infoya | Oakville, ON

October 2022 - June 2023

Worked on Home Depot website cart back-end team by using Java API Development, Spring & Spring Boot
technologies to develop web applications for client-server environments and worked on Microservices to add
functionalities, Google Cloud Platform (GCP) for analysis & application deployment, and code improvements to
existing applications. Worked in AGILE Methodology. Used technologies like Redis, Maven, Docker, Jenkins, Event
Driven architecture(CQRS), Git, JIRA.

Software Developer

June 2021 - February 2022

Korechi Innovations | Oshawa, ON

- Worked on a Mobile app using Java to manage and operate vehicle robots and their functionalities with Custom
 Views & Designs to fulfill requirements and used ROS Java to communicate with robot units locally.
- Implemented MVVM design pattern for **testability** and **reusability** of code and Implemented **WebRTC** to show the **video feed** from unit **cameras** with Integrated **Google Drive** to upload & download **files**.

D4D Software Pvt. Ltd | Mohali, Punjab, India

- Worked on a Health app for doctors & patients to manage & book appointments for surgeries and provide feedback
 for services rendered with Kotlin Language and implemented MVP design pattern and Camera & Video Recording
 features.
- Worked on an **E-Commerce** app using **Java** that engages customers in businesses with **Dependency Injection** (**Dagger2**) and **RESTful APIs** for the app data.
- Provided dedicated support and timely issue resolution to clients following successful app launch.

Software Developer

October 2016 - October 2018

DevelopTech IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd | Mohali, Punjab, India

- Worked on an E-Commerce app using Java that provides guidance for plants growth & enrichment with Realm
 Database and used Canvas to Draw Custom Views with Kotlin and MVP implementation.
- Worked on vocal social networking application with Social Network Integration and used Voice Filters to Recorded Voice.
- Worked on Health app which made a bridge between diagnostic labs and their customers with Socket Programming
 to implement chat service with users and Implemented Payment Gateway Integrations also RxJava and Retrofit to
 access REST APIs.
- Worked on laundry & dry-cleaning services app with **Material Guidelines** to improve App UI and Implemented **Payment Gateway** and **Third-Party UI** Libraries to provide better.
- Worked with teams from other projects and departments to create apps and data-driven by customer input.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

FoodCo - Java BackEnd Spring Boot application

July

It is an Food online food ordering appplication demonstration. Used **H2 Databse, Spring**

2023

Web, Microservies, MVC, SAGA and event driven(CQRS) design patterns.

EDUCATION

Post-graduation diploma - Web Design & Development

April 2021

Conestoga College, Kitchener, ON

GPA: 3.59

Academic Award: Distinction

Bachelor of Technology - Information Technology (IT)

May 2016

AGC, Amritsar, Punjab IN

LANGUAGE

EnglishHindiPunjabiFluentFluentNative